<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhu Yong</title>
    <link>http://zhuyong.me/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhu Yong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 22:46:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://zhuyong.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Blog From Octopress To Hugo</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2016/09/29/migrate-blog-from-octopress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 22:46:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2016/09/29/migrate-blog-from-octopress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s total 9 months since my last blog post, which was on 31 Dec 2015. It&amp;rsquo;s really a very long time. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am proud to announce I am back, and I just migrated the blog  from Octopress to Hugo. Reasons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Octopress no update for very long time, and I feel it&amp;rsquo;s complicated to setup the environment when I switch to new system. Second, Hugo is written in Golang, single executable program, I love it, and I love Golang. Some more reasons??? Still need more? Those two reasons are enough for me to spend last 2 night to migrate from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migration is easy, but existing posts might requrie edit if it has image and blockquote. Because I want to keep the Octopress classic theme, I just follow the instructions from &lt;a href=&#34;https://parsiya.net/categories/migration-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. After everything done, the blog pages looks almost same as Octopress version except there is no categories list in sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t write down detail steps here, all steps are in the link above. But I need to mention that I use back my old Octopress repository, which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yongzhy/yongzhy.github.io&#34;&gt;https://github.com/yongzhy/yongzhy.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, I backup the original Octopress &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch to &lt;code&gt;octopress_master&lt;/code&gt;, original &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; branch to &lt;code&gt;octopress_source&lt;/code&gt;, then replace all contents in &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; branch with content from Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to setup the blog environment on new system, I just need to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download hugo binary file from : &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Pygments &lt;code&gt;sudo pip install Pygments&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/john2x/solarized-pygment.git&#34;&gt;https://github.com/john2x/solarized-pygment.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone https://github.com/john2x/solarized-pygment.git
$ cd solarized-pygment
$ sudo python setup.py install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone this repository&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone -b source https://github.com/yongzhy/yongzhy.github.io.git
$ cd yongzhy.github.io.git
$ git subtree pull --prefix=public https://github.com/yongzhy/yongzhy.github.io.git master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo new post/newpost-title.markdown
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit post&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generate And Publish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo
$ bash deploy.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Day Of 2015</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/12/31/last-day-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 22:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/12/31/last-day-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In less than 2 hours, it will be brand new Year 2016. It&amp;rsquo;s annual summary time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the summary list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In April, whole family moved from very west to very east. We want to give the 2 boys better environment and it seems the decision is correct. Kids enjoyed to live in east because of so many fun places to go within short travel distance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Aug, whole family fly back to China for whole month, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful journey for the two boys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Oct, passed my driving test and got my driving license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Nov, bought my first car. I would say, it&amp;rsquo;s really expensive to own a car in Singapore, but the life will be much easier with a car, especially when we bring the two boys out. And the time spend on road between home and office is reduced by at least half.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Dec, 2nd son started his childcare school life and not get used to it yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For work, there is one failure attempt for job change, not worth to mention, failed at the 1st culture phone call. Too bad! Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s really a busy year, I was &amp;ldquo;outsourced&amp;rdquo; to another team to help product development, different working style and most importantly, the always tight schedule. I spent a lot of nights at home remote to company network to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2016, I want myself to always be prepared, so when opportunity comes, I am ready!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collected My New Car</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/27/collected-my-new-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 22:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/27/collected-my-new-car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Black Friday today, and this morning I collected my 2015 biggest shopping item : my Citroen Grand C4 Picasso. Oh Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At early morning, I arrived at C&amp;amp;C and the whole process took around 1+ hour because my rear number plate installation was loose, called the technician to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After drove to company, I spent long time to lock the car, no mater I lock use the remote key or use physical key, I only hear the click sound but it was not locked. After tried open &amp;amp; close all doors few times without effect. I suddenly realized that it might because of the extra remote key in my bag, which was in the car. After I took out the other key and tried lock again, it worked! I checked with other Citroen drivers, there are quite some people had same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At afternoon after drove home, my wife and I lead our two boys to the new car, they immediately love it and enjoyed the short ride around our neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only big problem is that I need to improve my parking skills. :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Toy: microsoft sculpt ergonomic desktop</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/20/new-toy-microsoft-sculpt-ergonomic-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 22:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/20/new-toy-microsoft-sculpt-ergonomic-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon received my new toy: the Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic Desktop set.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-20-Keyboard/microsoft.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;microsoft sculpt ergonomic desktop&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After using old IBM Model M keyboard for long time, it took me a while to get used to this new layout and feeling. Comparing to IBM Model M, the key travel distance is really short. This keyboard would be perfect if it&amp;rsquo;s mechanical switch keyboard. :) ( Yeah, the price might double as well ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad thing for this keyboard is the very strong plastic odor, it made me sick only after one hour usage. Hope the smell will disappear when I return to office next Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got COE at S$59200</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/19/got-coe-at-s59200/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 21:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/19/got-coe-at-s59200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the 2nd round of COE bid in Nov, thanks to the good sale result in 7 - 8 Nov car show @ Singpaore Expo, dealer were willing to bid COE at higher price. At around 3pm, the price was already exceed 4th Nov final price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept refreshing the web page to get the status. C &amp;amp; C put reserve price of S$59999 at 10:30am, then at around 3:50pm when the price going to hit S$59000, they revised the bid to S$60999, then I know I guaranteed to get one COE this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After COE,  C &amp;amp; C still need few days to settle :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to pay the remainning of down payment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settle loan from bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settle car insurance, I must say, the insurance premium is super high for new driver like me. Too bad I must take the appointed insurance from AIG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the front &amp;amp; rear camera, solar film and etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register the car under my name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, they will call me to collect the car. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the day to come!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repair Honeywell 50250-S After Plug Into 220V Power Supply</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/09/repair-honeywell-50250-s-after-plug-into-220v-power-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/09/repair-honeywell-50250-s-after-plug-into-220v-power-supply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because of forest fire from neighbour Indonesia, air quality for 2015 Augest and September in Singapore reached hazardous level for many days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all past hazardous day, it&amp;rsquo;s my job to move Honeywell 50250-S air purifier around, then one day, while I was having my dinner, my wife volunteered to do the job. And that&amp;rsquo;s it, she plugged the plug into 220V output from the transformer, and both the transfer and purifier burnt. As the result, we suffer the haze for long time until I repair it, and by that time, haze almost gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix the transformer is simple, just replace the fuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix the purifier is little bit difficult, first I can&amp;rsquo;t find online anything regarding disassemble 50250-S, I can only try to disassemble any parts that can be taken out, and finally figured out where the PCB is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when I saw the PCB, I feel that I can fix it, because only one component was burnt. After search around online, I figured out that&amp;rsquo;s a veristor, but there is no part number printed, bad luck. Next I took the PCB to Simlim Tower, visited different shops and asked around if they have the replacement for that veristor, luckily I found one from a shop at basement, the replacement component is 10D271K (standard veristor for 110V). By the way, the cost for two transformer fuse + one 10D271K is S$2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repair process is simple, just use solder iron take out old versiter and replace with this new one, connect back the PCB, turn on the purifier,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image of the burn veristor (in red circle)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-09-Honeywell/honeywell_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Honeywell 50250-S Repair&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Image after change the veristor to 10D271K (the blue color one).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-09-Honeywell/honeywell_02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Honeywell 50250-S Repair&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Image of the fixed Honeywell 50250-S, everything back to normal:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-09-Honeywell/honeywell_03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Honeywell 50250-S Repair&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordered My First Car</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/08/ordered-my-first-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 17:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/08/ordered-my-first-car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend, just after I received my official driving license, I ordered my first car - Citroen Grand C4 Picasso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons I chose Grand C4 Picasso are simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need MPV car, we have 6 family members, 5 seaters car not enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For MPV, I shortlisted Honda Stream, Toyota Wish and this Grand C4 Picasso. In Singapore Honda and Toyota cars are people&amp;rsquo;s Number 1 choice because the high reliability and relatively low maintenance cost. If the car dealer still carry Honda Stream, I might go for that car. As for Toyota Wish, it&amp;rsquo;s a quite old model, no change since 2009. As for Grand C4 Picasso, this is a new model, fuel efficient, and the dealer provide 5 years warranty + 5 years free service. Most importantly, I like both the interior and exterior of this car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-08-Car/GC4P.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Citroen Grand C4 Picasso&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to wait for the AD to bid the COE, settle car loan and insurance, then I can collect my car. Sadly, that&amp;rsquo;s at least 2-3 weeks waiting time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got My SG50 Driving License</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/06/got-my-sg50-driving-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 21:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/06/got-my-sg50-driving-license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I passed my driving test at ComfortDelGro Driving Center on 29 Oct 2015 with only 1 attempt. And I received my offcial driving license card delivered on 5 Nov 2015, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to get the card so fast, with only 1 week waiting time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UBI driving center is the one with lowest passing rate among all 3 driving school in Singapore. I engaged a private driving instructor because of its flexibility and the relatively lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To pass the driving test, here are some tips based on my experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, for each learning session on road, try to train yourself the judgement for speed and distance, especially those car coming from behind on the lane you are going to change to. Don&amp;rsquo;t be rush or panic for lane change fail, it&amp;rsquo;s learning session, safety is alway first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, be familiar with the road and the circuit. You can find CDC circuit with Google search. For the road, I use Google &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.maps.mytracks&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;My Tracks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; app to track my learning session, then use Google Street View to go through the road whenever I need. Below is screen capture from my handphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-06-Driving/mytrack_01.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google My Track&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-06-Driving/mytrack_02.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google My Track&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, try to book your test at off-peak time to avoid heavy traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forth, on actual test day, must must be confident, be calm, treat it same as normal learn session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Config Logitech Performance MX Zoom Button In Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/05/config-logitech-performance-mx-zoom-button-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 13:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/05/config-logitech-performance-mx-zoom-button-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The middle button (click wheel) on Logitech Performance MX is very very difficult to press. So I changed the &lt;code&gt;Zoom&lt;/code&gt; button to middle button on windows system. To do same setting under Ubuntu, follow the instructions below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install necessary software packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   sudo apt-get install xbindkeys xautomation xev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, use &lt;code&gt;xev&lt;/code&gt; to find the button number for &lt;code&gt;Zoom&lt;/code&gt; button. Just run &lt;code&gt;xev&lt;/code&gt; from command line, then click &lt;code&gt;Zoom&lt;/code&gt; button when your cursor is in the small white window. You will see somthing like below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ButtonPress event, serial 45, synthetic NO, window 0x2400001,
        root 0x24d, subw 0x0, time 3735892633, (75,111), root:(301,192),
        state 0x0, button 2, same_screen YES
    
    ButtonRelease event, serial 45, synthetic NO, window 0x2400001,
        root 0x24d, subw 0x0, time 3735892633, (75,111), root:(301,192),
        state 0x200, button 2, same_screen YES
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create default &lt;code&gt;xbindkeys&lt;/code&gt; config file with command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   xbindkeys --defaults &amp;gt; ~/.xbindkeysrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open file &lt;code&gt;~/.xbindkeysrc&lt;/code&gt; to add the following lines at end of the file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;quot;xte &#39;mouseclick 2&#39;&amp;quot;
    b:13+Release
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Hacked YouCompleteMe to Support Lamely Structured Projects</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/02/01/hacked-youcompleteme-to-support-lamely-structured-pojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 09:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/02/01/hacked-youcompleteme-to-support-lamely-structured-pojects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 1 Year ago, I attempted to hack &lt;code&gt;YouCompleteMe&lt;/code&gt; for clang code completion for a lamely structured project, that hacking worked, but the hacking was dirty. For background information, &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/21746668/configure-vim-youcompleteme-for-special-project-structure&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is my origin question on StackOverflow and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/02/20/hack-youcompleteme-and-libclang-for-lamely-structured-project/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the detail about my first dirty hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently when I looked at this hacking again, I thought there should be a better way, especially after I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/Rip-Rip/758615&#34;&gt;this code snippet&lt;/a&gt; from GitHub Gist. At the moment I saw the code, I had a strong feeling that I have found the solution, I just need to verify it. To make code completion success for &lt;code&gt;clang -cc1 -fsyntack-only -code-complete-at a.c:4:11 main.c&lt;/code&gt;, the source file to create &lt;code&gt;CXTranslationUnit&lt;/code&gt; should be &lt;code&gt;main.c&lt;/code&gt; and the source file to do &lt;code&gt;clang_codeCompleteAt&lt;/code&gt; should be &lt;code&gt;a.c&lt;/code&gt;. So I modified the code to pass one additional command line argument to be the file to create &lt;code&gt;TransicationUnit&lt;/code&gt;, then compile and run command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ./complete a.c 11 4 main.c
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the output, I confirmed this was a better way to hack &lt;code&gt;YouCompleteMe&lt;/code&gt; for my need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I found the correct direction, the rest was just spend time to code, test and debug, here is a summary for what I have modified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &lt;code&gt;cpp/ycm/ClangCompleter/TransicationUnit.cpp&lt;/code&gt;, function &lt;code&gt;TranslationUnit::CandidatesForLocation&lt;/code&gt;, take additional parameter &lt;code&gt;compfile&lt;/code&gt; to pass to &lt;code&gt;clang_codeCompleteAt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &lt;code&gt;cpp/ycm/ClangCompleter/CodeCompleter.cpp&lt;/code&gt;, function &lt;code&gt;ClangCompleter::CandidatesForLocationInFile&lt;/code&gt;, take additional parameter &lt;code&gt;compfile&lt;/code&gt; and pass this newly added parameter to &lt;code&gt;unit-&amp;gt;CandidatesForLocation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &lt;code&gt;ycmd/completers/cpp/clang_completer.py&lt;/code&gt;, function &lt;code&gt;ComputeCandidatesInner&lt;/code&gt;, follow the way &lt;code&gt;_FlagsForRequest&lt;/code&gt; is implemented, add new function to get the &lt;code&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; source file to create &lt;code&gt;TransicationUnit&lt;/code&gt; and pass that result to &lt;code&gt;CandidatesForLocationInFile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &lt;code&gt;ycmd/completers/cpp/flags.py&lt;/code&gt;, add the new function to get &lt;code&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; source file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &lt;code&gt;.ycm_extra_conf.py&lt;/code&gt; under project source directory, add function &lt;code&gt;ParentForFile&lt;/code&gt;, this function read input &lt;code&gt;.clang_input_file&lt;/code&gt;, which is the mapping for &lt;strong&gt;code-complete-at-file&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;TransicationUnit-file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a python script to generate the mapping file for &lt;strong&gt;code-complete-at-file&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;TransicationUnit-file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing to my first hacking, this round is very clean, only clang related part on &lt;code&gt;ycmd&lt;/code&gt; is modified, the client side remain untouched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have checked in the modifications to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yongzhy/ycmd&#34;&gt;my fork of &lt;code&gt;ycmd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at branch &lt;code&gt;lamely&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDB BTO Home Network DIY</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/01/06/hdb-bto-home-network-diy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 12:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/01/06/hdb-bto-home-network-diy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://absolutehonesty.wordpress.com/2014/05/31/hougang-parkview-i-want-my-internet/&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to DIY the network thing for my new HDB flat when I was shopping on Taobao in Nov. Followed the suggestion in that blog, I bought all necessary items from Taobao, but the network modules I bought are Cat 6 module, not 5E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Jan 03, my contractor went to my new HDB flat to install the lights we bought from Taobao, while they doing the lights installation, I was doing DIY job to change all RJ11 phone jacks to network RJ45 jacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the tools I used for this DIY job.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-000.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Start from bedrooms, change the RJ11 to RJ45 one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture is the original RJ11 panel.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-001.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Take off the cover from the panel.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-002.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Loosen the screws on the panel. The cable inside is already Cat 6 network cable. So I just need to change the modules and panels.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-003.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Put the color wires into each slot on the network module. Use pattern B&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-004.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Cut off the extra wires, put on the back cover.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-005.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Insert module into the panel.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-006.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Use back the origin screws to fasten the panel.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-007.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After all three bedrooms and the bomb shelter (Yes, I changed the module and panel in bomb shelter as well). The next job is tougher, I need to do add modules to all terminal in the power box behind the main gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the original lines.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-008.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After I connect the modules to all lines.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-009.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is the final work.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-010.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The whole process was not difficult, just need to be careful to match the color lines with the pattern on the modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T32Hook: Utility To Auto Hook Trace32</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/31/t32hook-utility-to-auto-hook-trace32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 15:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/31/t32hook-utility-to-auto-hook-trace32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is last day of 2014. I will use this 2014 last blog to write about the utility I recently developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my latest project, firmware code failed during test with power cycle on target. And the Lauterbach emulator can&amp;rsquo;t detect the &lt;code&gt;power on&lt;/code&gt; event on this target, so we can&amp;rsquo;t use the &lt;code&gt;power on&lt;/code&gt; event to automate initial script running. The failure only happens after power cycle, so I must let Trace32 run the setup script to enable the trace in order to capture the code running history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because previously I already did a utility to automate failure replay using Trace32 simulation, I know Trace32 has remote API to control the script running. So I come out with the idea to detect target power cycle from the message on serial port (target firmware will print some message on serial port), upon power cycle event happen, use remote API to command Trace32 to execute the setup script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QT already has the &lt;code&gt;The Simple Terminal&lt;/code&gt; example, so my development leverage on this example code and added Trace32 remote API code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the image of the main window for the final working product.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-31-t32hook/t32hook-001.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This the serial setting dialog, I didn&amp;rsquo;t change this part from the example code.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-31-t32hook/t32hook-002.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is the Trace32 remote setting dialog. Added options to specify the remote host, port, packet size, the setup script to run as well as text line to trigger setup script re-run.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-31-t32hook/t32hook-003.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The whole development take me few night time at home. My initial working version with everything hard coded, because we must solve the firmware issue ASAP. I use my spare time to make it configurable, so my colleagues with same need can use it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not my first utility written using QT, when I need to write GUI utility, I will always turn to QT, sometime use PyQT, sometime use the native C++ version. The latest version of QT already have support for Android and iOS, I may test water with the Android version some time later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 Year End Summary</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/29/2014-year-end-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 17:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/29/2014-year-end-summary/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s end of Year 2014 and it&amp;rsquo;s the time to write summary for this year. Year 2014 is just an ordinary year same as previous few years, the main reason is there were no much excited things happen. There were several good opportunities for me to change, but unfortunately, I didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare myself well and I missed all those opportunities. I really think developer should be already be ready for opportunities, you never know when will an opportunity appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to summarize my Year 2014, I grouped those things that worth mention here into few categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;big-change&#34;&gt;Big Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one thing can fit this category in 2014. On 31 July, I received email from HDB to inform us that we got queue No. 1 in HDB May 2014 sale of balance flats exercise. So I chose a new HDB 5 room flat from Costa Ris @ Pasir Ris, the location is good, very near to MRT station. My current flat location is also very good, 5 minutes walking distance to Boon Lay MRT, we decided to move to east side for better air quality and more places for kids to play. In the past two months, I was busy with new flat renovation. Every weekend I travel from very west of Singapore to very east of Singapore to monitor the renovation progress. The renovation is still in progress and we plan to move in after Chinese New Year 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gadgets-bought-in-year-2014&#34;&gt;Gadgets Bought In Year 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acer C720 ChromeBook : I have install Ubuntu on this Chromebook through crouton, for the whole year, this notebook was my main computer. I use ChromeOS to surf web and use Ubuntu to do development and blog writing. I really love this machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chromecast from Google : Mainly used to play videos from YouTube for my kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allure Eyewear: Call Of Duty Ghost : No use much after few months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HHKB Pro 2 Type-S : To me, the key feeling not so good as my old IBM Model S&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LG G Pro 2 : Good Phablet, nice battery life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SandDisk Extreme Pro 480GB SSD : Good deal from Amazon and very good performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuous-ongoing-efforts&#34;&gt;Continuous / Ongoing Efforts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answered some StackOverflow questions and earned few hundreds reputation points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought a domain and start writing blog on GitHub page. The first blog post was on 11 Dec 2013 and total of 34 blog posts have been published. From &lt;code&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/code&gt; report, now the blog has 800 page view per month, the number is not much, but I am glad that some of the posts did helped the readers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;Google Keep&lt;/code&gt; as my daily &lt;code&gt;ToDoList&lt;/code&gt; since 21 Jan 2014, so far it works well for my needs. Every morning I create a new task list with the date in title, then copy previous day&amp;rsquo;s incomplete task to this new list, and also add new tasks. Tasks may not be completed in sequence, or been listed for quite few days, but it&amp;rsquo;s OK, as long as I know there is this task need to be done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/code&gt; as my diary to record my two boys&amp;rsquo; remarkable event since 06 Dec 2013. I create one calendar for each boy, then share the calendars to my wife, both of us tried to update the calendars daily, so we won&amp;rsquo;t miss any valuable moment with the two boys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;books-i-have-read-in-2014&#34;&gt;Books I Have Read in 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs (Chinese Version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just for Fun - Linus Torvalds (Chinese Version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Among Thieves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunger Game I, II and III&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter (All 7 Books, Chinese Version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a simple 2048 clone in Golang, console version. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yongzhy/2048-console&#34;&gt;code here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a QT GUI tool to re-init Trace32 after detected target power cycle from the messages printed on serial port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HHKB Palm Rest Arrived</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/24/hhkb-palm-rest-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 09:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/24/hhkb-palm-rest-arrived/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My HHKB palm rest from Taobao arrived last Saturday, and I brought it to office on Monday. After use if for two days, I am totally satisfied with it. The build quality is good, size is just nice for HHKB, well polished, and no strange smell. The logo was customized very good, exactly same as my requirement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-24-HHKB-Palm-Rest/palm-rest.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should do a free advertisement for this Taobao shop: &lt;a href=&#34;http://item.taobao.com/item.htm?spm=a1z10.1.w4004-5284025914.3.hP74Q9&amp;amp;id=40499617063&#34;&gt;Taobao Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgraded My HP DV6-6144TX To SSD &#43; HDD</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/22/upgraded-my-hp-dv6-6144tx-to-ssd-plus-hdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 22:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/22/upgraded-my-hp-dv6-6144tx-to-ssd-plus-hdd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received my Sandisk Extreme Pro 480GB SSD on 17 Dec, on that night, immediately after my kids slept, I went to study room and replaced the internal Toshiba SATA II HDD to this SSD. Next I partitioned the drive and installed Windows 7 Ultimate, the waiting time for Windows booting was significantly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next on 18 Dec night, after I installed all drivers for Windows 7, I tried to install a Debian 7.7 system to another partition to make the computer dual boot. But I failed on first try, because non-free firmware required for the WIFI hardware, but the installer can&amp;rsquo;t load firmware from the bootable USB drive. So I prepared another USB thumbdrive dedicated for the non-free firmware on 19 Dec night, this time the installation process went smoothly and I have Debian 7.7 and Windows 7 dual booting..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 20 Dec, my shopping packages from Taobao were delivered, one of those packages is the SATA adapter to replace the DVD drive, this adapter only costed my RMB 27, which is very very cheap. On that night, I took out the DVD drive and replaced it with that adapter and the original Toshiba SATA II hard drive. So now my laptop has over 1TB hard drive capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the image of Sandisk Extreme Pro 480GB SSD

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/sandisk.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SATA adapter with Toshiba SATA II drive mounted

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/toshiba.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSD and SATA adapter installed on the system. The adapter doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the hole to mount screw at location 1, and its size is smaller than the original DVD drive, so it left some part un-covered at location 2. Considering the very cheap price, I am OK with the two not perfect point.

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/all.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>