<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DIY | Zhu Yong]]></title>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/categories/diy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-08T18:09:02+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zhuyong.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhu Yong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HDB BTO Home Network DIY]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/01/06/hdb-bto-home-network-diy/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T12:20:40+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/01/06/hdb-bto-home-network-diy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by <a href="https://absolutehonesty.wordpress.com/2014/05/31/hougang-parkview-i-want-my-internet/">this blog</a>, I decided to DIY the network thing for my new HDB flat when I was shopping on Taobao in Nov. Followed the suggestion in that blog, I bought all necessary items from Taobao, but the network modules I bought are Cat 6 module, not 5E.</p>

<p>On Jan 03, my contractor went to my new HDB flat to install the lights we bought from Taobao, while they doing the lights installation, I was doing DIY job to change all RJ11 phone jacks to network RJ45 jacks.</p>

<p>Below are the tools I used for this DIY job.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-000.jpg"></p>

<p>Start from bedrooms, change the RJ11 to RJ45 one by one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>This picture is the original RJ11 panel.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-001.jpg"></p>

<p>Take off the cover from the panel.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-002.jpg"></p>

<p>Loosen the screws on the panel. The cable inside is already Cat 6 network cable. So I just need to change the modules and panels.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-003.jpg"></p>

<p>Put the color wires into each slot on the network module. Use pattern B</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-004.jpg"></p>

<p>Cut off the extra wires, put on the back cover.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-005.jpg"></p>

<p>Insert module into the panel.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-006.jpg"></p>

<p>Use back the origin screws to fasten the panel.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-007.jpg"></p>

<p>After all three bedrooms and the bomb shelter (Yes, I changed the module and panel in bomb shelter as well). The next job is tougher, I need to do add modules to all terminal in the power box behind the main gate.</p>

<p>This is the original lines.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-008.jpg"></p>

<p>After I connect the modules to all lines.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-009.jpg"></p>

<p>This is the final work.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2015-01-06-network/network-010.jpg"></p>

<p>The whole process was not difficult, just need to be careful to match the color lines with the pattern on the modules.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
