<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhu Yong</title>
    <link>http://zhuyong.me/categories/car/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhu Yong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://zhuyong.me/categories/car/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Collected My New Car</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/27/collected-my-new-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 22:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/27/collected-my-new-car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Black Friday today, and this morning I collected my 2015 biggest shopping item : my Citroen Grand C4 Picasso. Oh Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At early morning, I arrived at C&amp;amp;C and the whole process took around 1+ hour because my rear number plate installation was loose, called the technician to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After drove to company, I spent long time to lock the car, no mater I lock use the remote key or use physical key, I only hear the click sound but it was not locked. After tried open &amp;amp; close all doors few times without effect. I suddenly realized that it might because of the extra remote key in my bag, which was in the car. After I took out the other key and tried lock again, it worked! I checked with other Citroen drivers, there are quite some people had same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At afternoon after drove home, my wife and I lead our two boys to the new car, they immediately love it and enjoyed the short ride around our neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only big problem is that I need to improve my parking skills. :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got COE at S$59200</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/19/got-coe-at-s59200/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 21:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/19/got-coe-at-s59200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the 2nd round of COE bid in Nov, thanks to the good sale result in 7 - 8 Nov car show @ Singpaore Expo, dealer were willing to bid COE at higher price. At around 3pm, the price was already exceed 4th Nov final price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept refreshing the web page to get the status. C &amp;amp; C put reserve price of S$59999 at 10:30am, then at around 3:50pm when the price going to hit S$59000, they revised the bid to S$60999, then I know I guaranteed to get one COE this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After COE,  C &amp;amp; C still need few days to settle :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to pay the remainning of down payment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settle loan from bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settle car insurance, I must say, the insurance premium is super high for new driver like me. Too bad I must take the appointed insurance from AIG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the front &amp;amp; rear camera, solar film and etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register the car under my name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, they will call me to collect the car. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the day to come!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordered My First Car</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/08/ordered-my-first-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 17:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2015/11/08/ordered-my-first-car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend, just after I received my official driving license, I ordered my first car - Citroen Grand C4 Picasso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons I chose Grand C4 Picasso are simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need MPV car, we have 6 family members, 5 seaters car not enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For MPV, I shortlisted Honda Stream, Toyota Wish and this Grand C4 Picasso. In Singapore Honda and Toyota cars are people&amp;rsquo;s Number 1 choice because the high reliability and relatively low maintenance cost. If the car dealer still carry Honda Stream, I might go for that car. As for Toyota Wish, it&amp;rsquo;s a quite old model, no change since 2009. As for Grand C4 Picasso, this is a new model, fuel efficient, and the dealer provide 5 years warranty + 5 years free service. Most importantly, I like both the interior and exterior of this car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2015-11-08-Car/GC4P.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Citroen Grand C4 Picasso&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to wait for the AD to bid the COE, settle car loan and insurance, then I can collect my car. Sadly, that&amp;rsquo;s at least 2-3 weeks waiting time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>