<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gadget | Zhu Yong]]></title>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/categories/gadget/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-26T12:24:04+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zhuyong.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhu Yong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Released Chromecast SDK : Countless Apps Coming]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/02/04/google-released-chromecast-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T09:39:48+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/02/04/google-released-chromecast-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After <a href="http://10.36.134.34:4000/blog/2014/01/25/i-received-my-chromecast/">received my Chromecast</a> for 10 days, I received good news from Google. Google finally <a href="http://chrome.blogspot.sg/2014/02/chromecast-is-now-open-to-developers.html">opened chromecast SDK to all developers</a>. This is what Chromecast users and developers waiting for long time. Developers now must be busy coding to integrate the SDK into their apps, so countless Chromecast-compatible apps would show-up any day now.</p>

<p>Media player apps will be the first batch to support Chromecast, especially for local media streaming. I think this is the most desired feature for most of Chromecast users including me. I use MX Player a lot, I can&rsquo;t wait to see it with Chromecast support.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t play games on phone, but I think there will be plenty of games with Chromecast support. People likes to play games on large screen, supporting for Chromecast would be a must have feature for any android games from now on.</p>

<p>For developers, check the two links below to start your development.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developers.google.com/cast/docs/downloads">Chromecast SDK Download</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developers.google.com/cast/docs/developers">Chromecast Developer Guide</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half Day With Allure Eyewear "Call of Duty : Ghost"]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/28/half-day-with-allure-eyewear-call-of-duty-ghost/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-28T17:42:29+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/28/half-day-with-allure-eyewear-call-of-duty-ghost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just before lunch time, security guard at reception desk called me to collect my parcel. I knew my 3 pieces of <code>Call Of Duty : Ghost</code> have arrived. I placed order on 23 Jan and it only takes 5 days for international shipping, the speed is fast enough for a US$20 delivery.</p>

<p>My excutement and happiness didn&rsquo;t last long until I opened the box and only see two pieces of eyeware inside. I immediately opened my order online and checked carefully, yes, the invoice stated clearly that I ordered 3 pieces of eyewear, but I only got 2 of them shipped. And there is only 1 shipment number, so I guess there won&rsquo;t be a second package on the way. Next I immediately sent an email through the online contact form, but I think it will take some hours before I got response due to the different timezone. Let&rsquo;s wait and see how <code>Allure</code> reply.</p>

<p>After lunch time, I clipped the eyewear onto my glass and used it for the whole afternoon. So here is how I feel about this eyewear with one afternoon experience:</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>I felt a little giddy at first, guess is due to the 0.2 diopter. But my eyes soon get used to it.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a little bit heavy for this clip-on eyewear + my glass</li>
<li>When the time I left company, my eyes didn&rsquo;t have strong dry feeling as usual. I can confirm this is not due to phychological factor. I can really feel it. Tomorrow I will use it for whole day, I think the feel will be clearer.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s troublesome to take off the eyewear when I left my cubicle to pantry or toilet, then put on again.</li>
</ul>


<p>Basically, this product worth the US$25 price, I would suggest this for anyone who work on computer for long hours. Of course, if you already wear glass and have the budget, I strongly suggest go to the <code>gunnar</code> customization option.</p>

<p><code>Update 2014-02-04</code> : I contacted <code>Allure</code> on 28 Jan, and they processed another shipment for the 3rd eyewear at U.S locat time <code>01/29/2014  5:19 P.M</code>. I must say their action and response was really fast. For this reason, I would recommend <code>Allure</code> to anyone that interested to buy eyeware to protect their eyes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Received My Chromecast]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/25/i-received-my-chromecast/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T10:13:48+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/25/i-received-my-chromecast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DR0PDNE/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DR0PDNE&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=zhuyong.me-20"><img class="left" src="/images/blogimg/2014-01-25-Chromecast.jpg" title="&ldquo;Chromecast On Amazon&rdquo;" ></a></p>

<p>I ordered Chromecast from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DR0PDNE/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DR0PDNE&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=zhuyong.me-20" title="">Amazon</a> one week back when it has promotional price of US$29.99 only.</p>

<p>I want to buy Chromecast even before I got my C720 Chromebook, but Chromecast is not selling in Singapore and it is not eligible for the free international shipping to Singapore for over US$125 spending, I don&rsquo;t want to spend over US$20 shipping fee to buy a product only cost US$29.99, so I wait.</p>

<p>One week earlier, I saw my colleage shopping on Amazon, and he always use Comegateway service to ship product from US to Singapore. So I ask if he can buy the Chromecast and ship together with his purchases. He happily agreed.</p>

<p>Yesterday afternoon, DHL delivered to our office, I pay my colleague total S$46 (S$40 for the Chromecast and S$6 for the shared shipping fee), that&rsquo;s very cheap.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After went back home, I plugged Chromecast in to the HDMI slot on my TV, connected the USB power, then run <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.chromecast.app">Chromecast</a> app from my Android phone, the setup process was very easy, then wait for Chromecast to finish firmware updating. After that, everything was ready, so I run Youtube app from my phone and cast the famous <code>"London Bridge is Falling Down"</code> animation for my son. The video streaming was very smooth, no legging, not buffering, overall experience was nice.</p>

<p>But, there are only limited android apps that have Chromecast support, and most of the supported apps can&rsquo;t be used in Singapore. The function I want most is to cast the photos and video on my phone to TV. I took a lot of pictures and video for my two boys, I want to let them see themselves on photo and video, and the phone screen is way too small.</p>

<p>Google, please release the full power of Chromecast!!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Ordered "Call of Duty: Ghosts Eyewear"]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/23/i-ordered-call-of-duty-ghosts-eyewear/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-23T15:54:29+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/01/23/i-ordered-call-of-duty-ghosts-eyewear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I placed an order for 3 pieces of <a href="http://call-of-duty-ghosts.allure-eyewear.com/">Call Of Duty Ghosts By Allure Eyewear</a>. One for myself and the other two for my colleagues.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2014-01-23-codg5-k.jpeg" title="&ldquo;Call Of Duy Ghosts By Allure Eyewear&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>One week ago, I didn&rsquo;t even know there are glasses specially designed for heavy computer user and gamers. One day, one of my colleagues said he was going to buy a glass from Amazon, ask me to search word <code>gunnar</code> to have a look. Then he said the glass can give eyes some relief for full day computer user like us, almost all professional gamer wear this kind of glass to protect their eyes. So I did some google about this eyewear. From reviews on various websites, the feedbacks are quite possitive and effective. So I decided to invest one to protect my precious eyes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I can&rsquo;t buy those widely available eyewear from <code>gunnar</code> because I am a shortsighted person, and I already wear a pair of glass. I need to find the clip-on type of eyewear, and I only found <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009OZSMEI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009OZSMEI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=zhuyong.me-20">this</a> from Amazon, and it was out of stock, some unknown sellers sell it over US$60 at that time. Then I visited homepage of <code>gunnar</code>, I can&rsquo;t find the clip-on type, but shortsighted people can order customized glasses with a much higher prices. We haven&rsquo;t tried this kind of glasses before, invest over US$250 for a customized glass without known its effect is kind of risky. So we decided to wait for the stock come back for the clip-on type.</p>

<p>This afternoon, I visited amazon again and found they got stock and the price is only US$33.99, that&rsquo;s much cheaper compare to US$60. Although we need to pay over S$50 shipping fee for 3 pieces of the eyewear, my colleagues and I decided to place the order. Only by then, I noticed this eyewear is from <code>Allure Eyewear</code> instead of <code>gunnar</code>, no wonder I can&rsquo;t find this type from <code>gunnar</code> official website. So I googled again for reviews on <code>Allure Eyewear</code>, again, the reviews are good. And one comments over a review article mentioned the official website of <code>Allure Eyewear</code> sell <code>Call Of Duty Ghosts</code> cheaper than this older <code>Call of Duty Black Ops II</code>. That&rsquo;s good information before I place order.</p>

<p>So I visited <code>Allure Eyewear</code> website, and indeed, the new type is cheaper, only sell at US$24.99. And there international shipping is only US$20, much cheaper than Amazon. Without further waiting, I placed order. It will take 5-7 business days for the shipping. I will write one review after I receive it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
