<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gadget | Zhu Yong]]></title>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/categories/gadget/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zhuyong.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-06T22:22:00+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zhuyong.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhu Yong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgraded My HP DV6-6144TX to SSD + HDD]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/22/upgraded-my-hp-dv6-6144tx-to-ssd-plus-hdd/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T22:18:37+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/22/upgraded-my-hp-dv6-6144tx-to-ssd-plus-hdd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I received my Sandisk Extreme Pro 480GB SSD on 17 Dec, on that night, immediately after my kids slept, I went to study room and replaced the internal Toshiba SATA II HDD to this SSD. Next I partitioned the drive and installed Windows 7 Ultimate, the waiting time for Windows booting was significantly reduced.</p>

<p>Next on 18 Dec night, after I installed all drivers for Windows 7, I tried to install a Debian 7.7 system to another partition to make the computer dual boot. But I failed on first try, because non-free firmware required for the WIFI hardware, but the installer can&rsquo;t load firmware from the bootable USB drive. So I prepared another USB thumbdrive dedicated for the non-free firmware on 19 Dec night, this time the installation process went smoothly and I have Debian 7.7 and Windows 7 dual booting..</p>

<p>On 20 Dec, my shopping packages from Taobao were delivered, one of those packages is the SATA adapter to replace the DVD drive, this adapter only costed my RMB 27, which is very very cheap. On that night, I took out the DVD drive and replaced it with that adapter and the original Toshiba SATA II hard drive. So now my laptop has over 1TB hard drive capacity.</p>

<p>This is the image of Sandisk Extreme Pro 480GB SSD
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/sandisk.jpg"></p>

<p>The SATA adapter with Toshiba SATA II drive mounted
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/toshiba.jpg"></p>

<p>SSD and SATA adapter installed on the system. The adapter doesn&rsquo;t have the hole to mount screw at location 1, and its size is smaller than the original DVD drive, so it left some part un-covered at location 2. Considering the very cheap price, I am OK with the two not perfect point.
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-12-22-ChangeDrive/all.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Cut My Sim Card to Micro-Sim]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/08/diy-cut-my-sim-card-to-micro-sim/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T16:31:49+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/08/diy-cut-my-sim-card-to-micro-sim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been weeks since I purchased my LG G Pro 2, but I haven&rsquo;t insert sim card into it yet. The reason is because my current sim card is the normal size sim card, but LG G Pro 2 needs micro-sim card. I checked with my Telco M1 customer service, they said they don&rsquo;t provide sim card cutting service, I must pay S$37 to get a micro-sim card. To me, this S$37 is too expensive, so I didn&rsquo;t buy from M1 and just use the new phone as a Tablet to surf net.</p>

<p>Last week during one day lunch time, I asked my coleagues where can I find sim card cutting service, one of my colleagues said he has a cutter but never used it before, so I asked him to bring the cutter to office. And he did it today, so I cut my sim card to micro-sim. With the cutter, the task was simple and easy. Attached a picture for the cutter and frame left from origin sim card.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2014-12-08-Simcard/2014-12-08-simcard.jpg" title="&ldquo;Cutter and remainning of normal sim card&rdquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crazy Shopping Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/27/crazy-shopping-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-27T22:41:50+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/27/crazy-shopping-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon, I ordered another gadget from Amazon:
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KHRYRLY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00KHRYRLY&linkCode=as2&tag=zhuyong.me-20&linkId=5VFWEDLJIRJOG7TM">SanDisk Extreme PRO 480GB SATA 6.0GB/s 2.5-Inch 7mm Height Solid State Drive (SSD) With 10-Year Warranty- SDSSDXPS-480G-G25</a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=zhuyong.me-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B00KHRYRLY" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KHRYRLY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B00KHRYRLY&linkCode=as2&tag=zhuyong.me-20&linkId=5VFWEDLJIRJOG7TM"><img border="0" src="http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&ASIN=B00KHRYRLY&Format=_SL250_&ID=AsinImage&MarketPlace=US&ServiceVersion=20070822&WS=1&tag=zhuyong.me-20" ></a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=zhuyong.me-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B00KHRYRLY" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p>When I start sourcing good SSD deal on Amazon, I was initially looking at Intel 730 480GB, few days back, it was on discount price of US$199.99. Intel SSD has 5 Years international warranty, then I found this SandDisk SSD was selling with 10 Years warranty, someone online said the warranty was international, but I can&rsquo;t find clear statement. So I contacted Amazon customer service, after confirmed the warranty is international, I asked the customer service can Amazon match the price with other online store. At the time I contact customer service, this 480GB SSD was listed around US$250, the other online store has discount of US$204. The customer service told me Amazon won&rsquo;t honor any price match. So I think I&rsquo;d better wait till Friday to see if got big discount. Then to my surprise, 3 minutes later, when I refresh the page, Amazon changed the price to US$204. So I immediately placed the order, and 2 of my colleagues also placed order on this same item.</p>

<p>This month for me is really a crazy shopping month. I have spend a lot on several different online stores:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ordered over S$2000 products from TaoBao, most of the items are for my new BTO HDB house renovation. Some package has not been shipped. I think all those items can only be delivered to my new house around end of Dec.</li>
<li>Ordered HHKB from Amazon Japan</li>
<li>Ordered LG G Pro 2 at Singapore</li>
<li>Ordered new house kitchen sink tap from Amazon. My purchase was US$206, when 25 Nov I received the product, I found Amazon has dropped the price to US$158, so I contacted customer service to refund the price difference. They granted the refund on the spot.</li>
<li>Ordered this SanDisk 480GB SSD</li>
<li>Ordered XiaoMi Power Bank, still on the way</li>
<li>Ordered backup battery for my old LG HD 4x from Aliexpress. Still on the way</li>
</ul>


<p>Ordered so many items, spending so much in one month just for online shopping. I never done this before, so worth mark it here. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HHKB Pro 2 Type-S After One Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/26/hhkb-pro-2-type-s-after-one-week/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-26T14:33:34+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/26/hhkb-pro-2-type-s-after-one-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My HHKB Pro 2 Type-S was delivered to my house on 19 Nov, so till today, I have officially owned it one week. So I think it&rsquo;s time to write down my feeling about this well designed keyboard.</p>

<p>Before I purchase HHKB, I have being using old IBM Model M SSK for two years, the feel for IBM Model M is superb, it&rsquo;s just too noisy. I should say sorry to colleagues whose seats near me. My work platform is Windows, and I use  Total Commander as my primary file manager. So my short review for HHKB would based on my daily usage scenario, with comparison to Model M.</p>

<h3>Pros:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Size, the super compact size, I love it</li>
<li>Key layout, for people use Emacs and VIM as their editor. Now on every computer I own, I will map <code>Caps Lock</code> to <code>Ctrl</code>, I just feel it&rsquo;s so convenient compare to <code>Ctrl</code> at left bottom corner.</li>
<li>Quite, compare to my old IBM Model M, it&rsquo;s so quite.</li>
<li>USB Hub, I put my Logitech Performance MX receiver on one of the two USB port.</li>
<li>Configurable, and have <code>Windows</code> key, of course, this is advantage compare to old Model M.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Cons:</h3>

<ul>
<li>USB cable location. If the USB was at left or right side of HHKB, it could be much better.</li>
<li>No dedicated function key, and arrow key, not convenient for Windows user with Total Commander like me.</li>
<li>Key press feeling not good as IBM Model M, no &lsquo;Click&rsquo; feeling</li>
<li>Key layout, unless you have HHKB connected to all your desktop / laptop, you will keep press <code>\</code> on computer without HHKB.</li>
</ul>


<p>Here is a picture of my two beloved keyboards.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blogimg/2014-11-26-HHKB/HHKB-001.jpg" title="&ldquo;HHKB and IBM Model M SSK&rdquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally, I Bought a HHKB Professional 2 Type-S]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/25/finally-hhkb-professional-type-s/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T08:49:10+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/25/finally-hhkb-professional-type-s</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Same as many programmers using Emaces or VIM, I want to own a HHKB professional for real long time, and for the same reason not many people buy it: the price. This keyboard is really expensive when compare to other mechanical keyboard. But deep in my heart, I always want to own one. So this month when I want to replace my IBM model M SSK from workplace, I decided to buy a HHKB Professional 2 Type-s. Japanese Yen has being drop for a long period, so I think it&rsquo;s a good time to buy products from Japan.</p>

<p>I decided to buy from Japan <a href="http://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B008GXT6SK?ref_=pe_492632_169829912_TE_M3T1_dp_1">Amazon</a>, then use <a href="http://www.jshoppers.com/forward/">JShoppers</a> to forward the package to Singapore. The process is straight forward. The reason I choose JShoppers is because of its cheaper price. The whole process is same as all other forwarding service company:</p>

<ol>
<li>Register at JShopers, you will get a unique shipping address.</li>
<li>Shopping on Amazon, shipping address use the address provided by JShoppers.</li>
<li>Wait for package to be delivered to JShoppers and they will send you an email to ask you to pay the forwarding fee.</li>
<li>Pay forwarding fee.</li>
<li>Wait for your package to be delivered to your door.</li>
</ol>


<p>My experience with JShopper this time was not very good, mainly because of the verification process. Only after my HHKB was shipped by Amazon then I realized JShoppers requires ID verification. But they didn&rsquo;t mention this in the registration page and the email after registration. Somehow, my account password was sent in plain text in the email. Which makes me think they store customers' password in plain text in database. This is a really bad practice, and I did express my concern about their online system security and possible leakage of my private information (including the uploaded verification document). Customer support told me I can upload verification documents with some parts covered, only name, date of birth and address must be shown, but the ID verification department rejected my uploaded document. So I forwarded the email from customer support to the ID verification department, then they passed my ID verification. Funny! There is one more detail make me more concern about my private information. The first email from the ID verification department was written in Simplified Chinese to inform me about failed verification, this make me think JShoppers outsourced the ID verification to China company. Anyway, I wrote so much, just to say JShoppers is not doing good to make customers feel safe about their private information.</p>

<p>The waiting time for this forward service is long, because they are seeing large amount of package recently. My packaged delivered to JShoppers on 10 Nov, only been processed on 15 Nov, and notify me to pay forwarding fee on 17 Nov, after that, the speed was fast: shipment was on 18 Nov and delivered to me on 19 Nov.</p>

<p>Ok, let&rsquo;s forget about JShoppers, here comes the exciting part, the HHKB. Amazon use a big box for the relatively small keyboard.
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-001.jpg" title="&ldquo;HHKB In Amazon&rsquo;s Huge Box&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>HHKB box
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-002.jpg" title="&ldquo;HHKB In Box&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>HHKB box opened
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-003.jpg" title="&ldquo;HHKB In Box&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>HHKB connected to my chromebook.
<img src="/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-004.jpg" title="&ldquo;HHKB Connected To Chromebook&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>I will write another blog later about how I feel it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
