<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhu Yong</title>
    <link>http://zhuyong.me/categories/hhkb/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhu Yong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://zhuyong.me/categories/hhkb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HHKB Palm Rest Arrived</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/24/hhkb-palm-rest-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 09:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/12/24/hhkb-palm-rest-arrived/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My HHKB palm rest from Taobao arrived last Saturday, and I brought it to office on Monday. After use if for two days, I am totally satisfied with it. The build quality is good, size is just nice for HHKB, well polished, and no strange smell. The logo was customized very good, exactly same as my requirement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-12-24-HHKB-Palm-Rest/palm-rest.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should do a free advertisement for this Taobao shop: &lt;a href=&#34;http://item.taobao.com/item.htm?spm=a1z10.1.w4004-5284025914.3.hP74Q9&amp;amp;id=40499617063&#34;&gt;Taobao Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HHKB Pro 2 Type-S After One Week</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/26/hhkb-pro-2-type-s-after-one-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 14:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/26/hhkb-pro-2-type-s-after-one-week/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My HHKB Pro 2 Type-S was delivered to my house on 19 Nov, so till today, I have officially owned it one week. So I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to write down my feeling about this well designed keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I purchase HHKB, I have being using old IBM Model M SSK for two years, the feel for IBM Model M is superb, it&amp;rsquo;s just too noisy. I should say sorry to colleagues whose seats near me. My work platform is Windows, and I use  Total Commander as my primary file manager. So my short review for HHKB would based on my daily usage scenario, with comparison to Model M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size, the super compact size, I love it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key layout, for people use Emacs and VIM as their editor. Now on every computer I own, I will map &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt;, I just feel it&amp;rsquo;s so convenient compare to &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; at left bottom corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quite, compare to my old IBM Model M, it&amp;rsquo;s so quite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB Hub, I put my Logitech Performance MX receiver on one of the two USB port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configurable, and have &lt;code&gt;Windows&lt;/code&gt; key, of course, this is advantage compare to old Model M.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB cable location. If the USB was at left or right side of HHKB, it could be much better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No dedicated function key, and arrow key, not convenient for Windows user with Total Commander like me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key press feeling not good as IBM Model M, no &amp;lsquo;Click&amp;rsquo; feeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key layout, unless you have HHKB connected to all your desktop / laptop, you will keep press &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; on computer without HHKB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a picture of my two beloved keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-11-26-HHKB/HHKB-001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HHKB and IBM Model M SSK&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, I Bought a HHKB Professional 2 Type-S</title>
      <link>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/25/finally-hhkb-professional-type-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 08:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhuyong.me/blog/2014/11/25/finally-hhkb-professional-type-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Same as many programmers using Emaces or VIM, I want to own a HHKB professional for real long time, and for the same reason not many people buy it: the price. This keyboard is really expensive when compare to other mechanical keyboard. But deep in my heart, I always want to own one. So this month when I want to replace my IBM model M SSK from workplace, I decided to buy a HHKB Professional 2 Type-s. Japanese Yen has being drop for a long period, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to buy products from Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to buy from Japan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B008GXT6SK?ref_=pe_492632_169829912_TE_M3T1_dp_1&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, then use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jshoppers.com/forward/&#34;&gt;JShoppers&lt;/a&gt; to forward the package to Singapore. The process is straight forward. The reason I choose JShoppers is because of its cheaper price. The whole process is same as all other forwarding service company:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register at JShopers, you will get a unique shipping address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shopping on Amazon, shipping address use the address provided by JShoppers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for package to be delivered to JShoppers and they will send you an email to ask you to pay the forwarding fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay forwarding fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for your package to be delivered to your door.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with JShopper this time was not very good, mainly because of the verification process. Only after my HHKB was shipped by Amazon then I realized JShoppers requires ID verification. But they didn&amp;rsquo;t mention this in the registration page and the email after registration. Somehow, my account password was sent in plain text in the email. Which makes me think they store customers&amp;rsquo; password in plain text in database. This is a really bad practice, and I did express my concern about their online system security and possible leakage of my private information (including the uploaded verification document). Customer support told me I can upload verification documents with some parts covered, only name, date of birth and address must be shown, but the ID verification department rejected my uploaded document. So I forwarded the email from customer support to the ID verification department, then they passed my ID verification. Funny! There is one more detail make me more concern about my private information. The first email from the ID verification department was written in Simplified Chinese to inform me about failed verification, this make me think JShoppers outsourced the ID verification to China company. Anyway, I wrote so much, just to say JShoppers is not doing good to make customers feel safe about their private information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waiting time for this forward service is long, because they are seeing large amount of package recently. My packaged delivered to JShoppers on 10 Nov, only been processed on 15 Nov, and notify me to pay forwarding fee on 17 Nov, after that, the speed was fast: shipment was on 18 Nov and delivered to me on 19 Nov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s forget about JShoppers, here comes the exciting part, the HHKB. Amazon use a big box for the relatively small keyboard.

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HHKB In Amazon&amp;#39;s Huge Box&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HHKB box

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-002.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HHKB In Box&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HHKB box opened

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-003.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HHKB In Box&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HHKB connected to my chromebook.

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://zhuyong.me/images/blogimg/2014-11-25-HHKB/HHKB-004.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HHKB Connected To Chromebook&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will write another blog later about how I feel it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>